<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Week 1: Development Tools on PSU Astro 528</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/lessons/week1/</link><description>Recent content in Week 1: Development Tools on PSU Astro 528</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://psuastro528.github.io/lessons/week1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Learning goals</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/lessons/week1/goals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/lessons/week1/goals/</guid><description>Week 1 Understand course goals, overview, organization Recognize opportunities to improve producitivty through software development practices Exercise 1: Use software development tools Access ICDS-ACI Portal&amp;rsquo;s Jupyter Notebook Server using Julia Kernel Optionally access Julia+Git on your own computer Use Git &amp;amp; GitHub.com for retreiving and submitting lab assignments Exercise 2: Floating Point Arithmetic, Functions, Tests Write code as a function Use/write tests of code Become vigilant about potential pitfalls with floating-point arithmetic Exercise 3: Develop personal goals for semester Lessons along the way Strings, Modules, Namespace, Types, include Packages, Functions, Docstrings, Pseudo-random numbers, Broadcasting, Single &amp;amp; double precssion, Type stability, Online algorithms Write markdown text</description></item><item><title>Readings</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/lessons/week1/read/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/lessons/week1/read/</guid><description>Week 1: Prior to Monday&amp;rsquo;s class Think Julia Ch 1: The Way of the Program Github tutorial (at least through “Fork a Repo”) Prior to Thursday&amp;rsquo;s class The Rationale for Julia: Getting Started with Julia Programming (6pgs avaliable via &amp;ldquo;First Pages&amp;rdquo; as Preview/&amp;ldquo;Look Inside!&amp;quot;) Writing Scientific Software Ch 2 (22pgs): Scientific Computation and numerical analysis Start Lab 1 If it will help you with the lab: Think Julia Ch 2: Variables, Expressions &amp;amp; Statements</description></item><item><title>Course Overview (slides)</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/lessons/week1/course_overview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/lessons/week1/course_overview/</guid><description>## Welcome Penn State Astro 528 High-Performance Scientific Computing for Astrophysics Eric Ford --- ## Safety &amp; Respect ___ ### University Policy As of June 28, masks are optional for those who are fully vaccinated (two weeks after the second dose in a two-dose series or two weeks after a single-dose vaccine), including in classroom, advising, and student services spaces. Unvaccinated individuals must continue to wear masks indoors at all times.</description></item><item><title>Exercises</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/lessons/week1/lab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/lessons/week1/lab/</guid><description>Tools, Floating Point Arithmetic, Functions, Tests (Due Aug 29)
Exercise 1: Core development tools ICDS-ACI portal git GitHub.com Julia Jupyter Notebooks Pluto Notebooks Exercise 2: Floating Point Arithmetic, Functions, Tests Exercise 3: Personal Goals (save at least 15 minutes for this one) If you&amp;rsquo;re waiting on getting your account on ICDS-ACI, then I&amp;rsquo;d suggest that you start with exercise 3, since thinking about your goals does not require any accounts or special software.</description></item><item><title>Discussion Topics Week 1</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/lessons/week1/discuss/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/lessons/week1/discuss/</guid><description># Discussion Topics Astro 528, Week 1 High-Performance Scientific Computing for Astrophysics --- ## What makes scientific software special? Note: Floating-point arithmetic, Numerically intensive, Large data sets, Sophisticated tool sets, Rapidly changing specifications. All also show up in other applications. ___ ## Comparing to Computer Software Industry - How is scientific sofware development different? - ...similar? --- ## Floating Point Arithmetic - When should we be paranoid? - What can we do about it?</description></item></channel></rss>