<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lab Exercises on PSU Astro 528</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/submitting/</link><description>Recent content in Lab Exercises on PSU Astro 528</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/submitting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Starting Labs</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/submitting/starting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/submitting/starting/</guid><description>Instructions for Starting Labs via ICS ACI Portal Clone your Github Repository on ACI (only need to do once per assignment) Open notebook Save and commit changes as you go Clone your github repository to begin a new assignment Request a &amp;ldquo;BYOE Jupyter server&amp;rdquo; session via the ACI portal (see getting started) While waiting for it to start, let&amp;rsquo;s get the url for the repo to be cloned.</description></item><item><title>Committing changes</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/submitting/commit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/submitting/commit/</guid><description> Make sure you&amp;rsquo;ve saved all your changes (Ctrl+S) To commit changes to a single file: git add ex1.jl git commit -m &amp;#34;note describing this change&amp;#34; To commit your work on all files beginning with ex: git add ex* git commit -m &amp;#34;note describing these changes&amp;#34;</description></item><item><title>Testing your labs</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/submitting/testing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/submitting/testing/</guid><description>Test your code Make sure you&amp;rsquo;ve saved all your changes (Ctrl+S) Make sure you&amp;rsquo;ve committed your changes to your local repository. Check that your code passes any tests embedded in each notebook as you go. To test a single exercise, you can use a terminal window, change into your repo directory, and run either: julia --project test test/test1.jl To test al the exercises, you can run julia --project test test/runtests.</description></item><item><title>Submitting Labs</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/submitting/submitting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/submitting/submitting/</guid><description>Commit your changes Convert any Jupyter notebooks to Markdown Commit your work and Push to Github Review the feedback on your submission Before you submit Ideally, you&amp;rsquo;d commit small changes as you go. At a minimum, make sure that you commit your changes to your local repository each time you are wrapping up a coding session or about to take a break. Consider testing your code on ACI (or you local computer) before submitting the final version of your code.</description></item><item><title>Logging out</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/submitting/exiting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/submitting/exiting/</guid><description>When you&amp;rsquo;re all done with a lab (or just done for now):
Save all changes to notebooks (Ctrl+S) Commit any changes to your repository, consider pushing those commits to GitHub. Close browser tabs for your Pluto session, any Jupyter notebooks, and the Jupyter Lab tab. Go back to the &amp;ldquo;My Interactive Sessions&amp;rdquo; tab in the ACI Portal, click &amp;ldquo;Delete&amp;rdquo; for this Sessions and confirm.</description></item></channel></rss>