<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Week 7: Parallel Computing on PSU Astro 528</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/lessons/week7/</link><description>Recent content in Week 7: Parallel Computing on PSU Astro 528</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://psuastro528.github.io/lessons/week7/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Learning goals</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/lessons/week7/goals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/lessons/week7/goals/</guid><description>Week 7 Project Provide constructive feedback in code review Use GitHub Issues to manage tasks for code base Readings / Discussions Evaluating the suitability of a problem for different parallel architectures</description></item><item><title>Serial Code for Project due</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/lessons/week7/project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/lessons/week7/project/</guid><description>At this point the code does not need to be optimized. If you have time, it would be best to include the results of benchmarking and/or profiling in the README, to help both you and the reviewer identify which sections are ammenable to optimization.
Grading Rubric Code performs proposed tasks (1 point) Comprehensive set of unit tests, at least one integration or regression test (1 point) Code passes tests (1 point) Student code uses a version control system effectively (1 point) Repository includes many regular, small commits (1 point) Documentation for functions&amp;rsquo; purpose and design (1 point) Comprehensive set of assertions (1 point) Variable/function names consistent, distinctive &amp;amp; meaningful (1 point) Useful &amp;amp; consistent code formatting &amp;amp; style (1 point) Code is modular, rather than having chunks of same code copied and pasted (1 point) Preparing Your Own Code for Review Provide overview to help reviewer Please provide your reviewers with a README or other instructions to help them figure out how to spend their time reviewing your code in a way that is most likely to be helpful to you.</description></item></channel></rss>