<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Resources on PSU Astro 528</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/resources/</link><description>Recent content in Resources on PSU Astro 528</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://psuastro528.github.io/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Online Textbooks &amp; Tutorials</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/resources/textbooks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/resources/textbooks/</guid><description>Julia Think Julia: How to Think Like a Computer Scientist Related Courses Applications of Parallel Computers (UC Berkeley CS 267) Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory Introduction to Parallel Computing by Blaise Barney OpenMP Message Passing Interface (MPI) OpenACC slides from NVIDIA Texas Advanced Computing Center Introduction to High-Performance Computing by Eijkhout, Chow &amp;amp; van de Geijn (2006) Parallel Programming in MPI and OpenMP by Eijkhout (2017) &amp;mdash; pdf version &amp;mdash; source Improve this page You can add your suggestions by submitting a pull request for editing this file&amp;rsquo;s source.</description></item><item><title>Software</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/resources/software/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/resources/software/</guid><description>Julia Julia Manual Think Julia: How to Think Like a Computer Scientist Introcution to Applied Linear Algebra: Vectors, Matrices and Least Squares: Julia Language Companion The Fast Track to Julia 1.0 Learn Julia in Y Minutes Why Julia? Julia Tutorials Julia Blog Julia Discourse Forum Julia on StackOverflow Julia on Reddit Julia Twitter feed Julia Slack channel Jupyter DataQuest Tutorial on Jupyter Setting up Jupyter for Julia Jupyter with multiple languages Diffing Jupyter notebooks Binder for sharing Jupyter notebooks Git GitHub Guides Git for Everyone Data Camp on Git Git Desktop Linux Command Line Data Camp on Shell Docker Docker Orientation Docker for homework exercises: Github Repo Cloud.</description></item><item><title>Hardware Resources</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/resources/hardware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/resources/hardware/</guid><description>Penn State Resources Roar: Institue for Computational &amp;amp; Data Sciences&amp;rsquo;s Advanced CyberInfrastructure (ICDS-ACI) Getting Started on ICS-ACI Roar User&amp;rsquo;s Guide Roar Training Series Roar On-demand Tutorial Videos Open On Demand Portal (written for OSU, but much of info is similar) Cloud Computing Penn State Cloud Program Cloud Computing Amazon EC2 Google Compute Engine Google Colaboratory GPU acceleration for Julia using Google Colaboratory Domino Data Labs Improve this page You can add your suggestions by submitting a pull request for editing this file&amp;rsquo;s source.</description></item><item><title>Additional Resources</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/resources/other/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/resources/other/</guid><description>Academic Success, Learning Assistance, &amp;amp; Student Resources The Eberly College of Science is committed to the academic success of students enrolled in the College&amp;rsquo;s courses and undergraduate programs. When in need of help, students can utilize various College and University wide resources for learning assistance. For more information see: http://www.science.psu.edu/advising/success/.</description></item></channel></rss>