<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Making of Astro528 on PSU Astro 528</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/tools_used/</link><description>Recent content in The Making of Astro528 on PSU Astro 528</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://psuastro528.github.io/tools_used/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Technology used</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/tools_used/tools_used/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/tools_used/tools_used/</guid><description>Tools for Creating &amp;amp; Maintaining Course Content GitHub Share lessons &amp;amp; assignments, version control, backup Provide feedback to students via pull requests Hosts website, lesson, assignments GitHub Classroom For distributing lessons &amp;amp; assignments via individual private repositories, providing feedback via GitHub pull requests. Julia Programming language For a modern high-performance high-level programming language capable of parallelization at all scales Pluto notebooks For integrated lessons, tutorials, labs encouraging literate computing and avoiding confusion due to notebook state Jupyter notebooks For integrated lessons, tutorials, labs encouraging literate computing Julia Markdown: For integrating documentation and code with human-readable version control Weave: Converts draft Jupyter notebooks into Julia Markdown Quickly update and regenerate Jupyter notebooks from updated Julia Markdown.</description></item><item><title>Creating lab assignments</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/tools_used/creating_labs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/tools_used/creating_labs/</guid><description>Workflow for creating lab assignments Create Development repostiory from template: Create an empty private repository named labN-dev at GitHub. Go to https://github.com/PsuAstro528, click New Repository Name: labN-dev Description: Lab N Private Uncheck Initialize README, .gitignore: None, License: None Create repository- Change into directory of lab exercises Change into directory of lab exercises cd ~/Teach/Astro528/Fall2021/exercises git clone git@github.com:PsuAstro528/labN-dev.git cd labN-dev copy files from template repository (lab-template) into labN-dev directory cp .</description></item><item><title>Reviewing lab assignments</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/tools_used/reviewing_labs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/tools_used/reviewing_labs/</guid><description>Workflow for reviewing lab assignments Go to GitHub Classroom
Click class Click Assignment To review a student&amp;rsquo;s work:
Click &amp;ldquo;View repository&amp;rdquo; next to student&amp;rsquo;s github id Look if &amp;ldquo;Pull requests&amp;rdquo; has a number &amp;gt;=1 after it. If so: Click &amp;ldquo;Pull requests&amp;rdquo;, click pull request name Click &amp;ldquo;Checks&amp;rdquo; and see that Travis returns &amp;ldquo;Succes&amp;rdquo; Click &amp;ldquo;Files changed&amp;rdquo; Click &amp;ldquo;File filter&amp;hellip;&amp;quot;, select .jmd (or click &amp;ldquo;Jump to&amp;hellip;&amp;quot;, select ex.</description></item><item><title>Creating the website</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/tools_used/setup_website/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/tools_used/setup_website/</guid><description>Creating the Website for Astro 528 Astro 528&amp;rsquo;s website uses the Hugo, a fast static-site generator, the DocDock theme theme, Reveal.js for building slide decks to organize class discussion and serve as a reference for students outside of classroom, and and GitHub pages for html hosting.
Unforuntatley, I didn&amp;rsquo;t take detailed notes on the initial setup. Basically, I followed the instructions here, using option 1 (&amp;ldquo;Install DocDock as git submodule&amp;rdquo;). For customizations, see:</description></item><item><title>Updating the website</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/tools_used/update_website/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/tools_used/update_website/</guid><description>Updating the Website for Astro 528 Astro 528 uses the hugo static site generator, the docdock theme, github pages for html hosting, and github actions for triggering builds. Once those are setup, then updating the website can be done as follows:
Change into the website source directory, pull any updates from other machines, and start the hugo server locally
cd Teach/Astro528/Spring2019/Spring2019-website-src git pull hugo server Only edit files in content folder and its subfolders.</description></item><item><title>Symposium for Teaching &amp; Learning with Technology 2020</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/tools_used/tlt2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/tools_used/tlt2020/</guid><description>Integrating Jupyter Notebooks, Version Control, and GitHub Classroom
Eric Ford
Dept. of Astronomy &amp;amp; Astrophysics
Note: Jupyter Notebooks enable instructors and students to integrate text, equations, figures, and computer code into lessons and assignments. Git, a distributed version control system, enables multiple contributors such as instructors, students, colleagues to efficiently update and improve curricular materials and assignments. GitHub Classroom allows instructors to see student submissions and provide detailed feedback on their work.</description></item><item><title>Acknowledgments</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/tools_used/ackl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/tools_used/ackl/</guid><description>Acknowledgments People Justin Petucci of ICS-ACI for providing instructions on setting up the Jupyter Notebook server to work with a Julia kernel. Michael Potter of ECoS Digital Learning for help creating Docker container/image for running Jupyter Notebook server with a Julia kernel. Adam Lavely, Christopher Blanton &amp;amp; Chuck Pavloski for helping to find online resources (from their CSE 597 course) Hardware ICS-ACI for providing classroom support CyberLAMP team &amp;amp; NSF for providing GPU and Phi resources</description></item></channel></rss>