<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Peer Code Reviews on PSU Astro 528</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/project/code_reviews/</link><description>Recent content in Peer Code Reviews on PSU Astro 528</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://psuastro528.github.io/project/code_reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Preparing your Code for Review</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/project/code_reviews/prep/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/project/code_reviews/prep/</guid><description>Preparing Your Own Code for Review Provide overview to help reviewer Please provide your reviewers with a README or other instructions to help them figure out how to spend their time reviewing your code in a way that is most likely to be helpful to you.
Make sure code is in plain text files (i.e., not only Jupyter notebooks) Jupyter and Pluto notebooks are great to document how to use your code.</description></item><item><title>How to Conduct Code Review</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/project/code_reviews/how_to/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/project/code_reviews/how_to/</guid><description>Once you&amp;rsquo;ve been granted permission to a repository to review, browse to the repository on GitHub, take a look at the README (or whatever other documentation they provided).
Next, browse the source files on GitHub by clicking on the file to review. Try to provide specific feedback on potential opporunities for improvement in each of the categories listed below. In most cases, I think it will generally be easiest to create a new issue for each suggestion linked to the line(s) of codes that you&amp;rsquo;re commenting on (see below for step-by-step instructions).</description></item><item><title>Follow-up on your Code Review</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/project/code_reviews/follow_up/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/project/code_reviews/follow_up/</guid><description>Making use of your code review On GitHub, browse to your repository and click the &amp;ldquo;Issues&amp;rdquo; tab. Then you should have a list of all the issues that have been created. You can click on each issue&amp;rsquo;s name to see the specific lines of code they cited and to read the reviewer&amp;rsquo;s full comments. Some suggestions will clearly be good ideas and easy to fix quickly. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve updated the code as appropraite (commited and pushed that change), then you can enter &amp;ldquo;Done&amp;rdquo; in the box at the bottom and click &amp;ldquo;Close issue&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Rubric for Peer Review</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/project/code_reviews/rubric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/project/code_reviews/rubric/</guid><description>Grading Rubric for Assessing the Peer Review Constructive suggestions for improving programming practices (1 point) Specific, constructive suggestions for improving code readability/documentation (1 point) Specific, constructive suggestions for improving tests and/or assertions (1 point) Specific, constructive suggestions for improving code modularity/organization/maintainability (1 point) Specific, constructive suggestions for improving code efficiency (1 point) Finding any bugs (if code author confirms) (bonus points?)</description></item></channel></rss>