<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Using ICDS-ACI/Roar on PSU Astro 528</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/aci/</link><description>Recent content in Using ICDS-ACI/Roar on PSU Astro 528</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/aci/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creating Account on Roar</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/aci/create_account/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/aci/create_account/</guid><description>Create Account at ICDS-ACI/Roar All students should request an ACI account before the second class meeting.
On the account request form,
specify ebf11 as the sponsor account, list Astro528 as the research description, leave computational and Data Requirements box blank (since they already know what will be required for the class.) Students who already have an ACI account should contact i-ASK to request that they add your account to the Astro 528 group.</description></item><item><title>Initial Setup on Roar</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/aci/initial_setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/aci/initial_setup/</guid><description>Initial Setup for Roar / ICDS-ACI Request an account on &amp;ldquo;Roar&amp;rdquo;, the supercomputing facility run by Penn State&amp;rsquo;s Institute for Computational and Data Science (ICDS) Advanced CyberInfrastructure (ACI) group.
Once your account is active, go to the ACI portal, go to Clusters._ACI Shell Access.
Run &amp;lsquo;/gpfs/group/RISE/classroom/astro_528/scripts/updateKeys.sh’ to setup your ssh keys on ACI. You can accept most of the default prompts, but I recommend that you do NOT enter a password for your ssh key (we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss why in a few weeks).</description></item><item><title>Pluto Notebooks on ACI</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/aci/pluto/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/aci/pluto/</guid><description>Start a JupyterLab server configured to offer the Julia kernel on ACI Each time in the future you want to start a Jupyter notebook session on ICDS-ACI.
Make sure you have an account on ACI and have completed the initial setup Browse to portal.aci.ics.psu.edu Login (if necessary) Click Interactive Apps on top menu Choose BYOE Jupyter Server_ Select: Jupyter Interface: JupyterLab Environment setup: TODO UPDATE ME Allocation: ebf11_d_g_gc_default Number of hours: 2 hours Node type: ACI-b GPU (either No GPU or 1 GPU) Memory per core: 4 GB Click Launch Wait while your job starts Once the Connect to JupyterLab Server button appears, click it The top row of tiles (labeled &amp;ldquo;Notebook&amp;rdquo;) should include a tile labeled &amp;ldquo;Pluto.</description></item><item><title>Jupyter Notebooks on ACI</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/aci/jupyter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/aci/jupyter/</guid><description>Start a JupyterLab server configured to offer the Julia kernel on ACI Each time in the future you want to start a Jupyter notebook session on ICDS-ACI.
Make sure you have an account on ACI and have completed the initial setup Browse to portal.aci.ics.psu.edu Login (if necessary) Click Interactive Apps on top menu Choose BYOE Jupyter Server_ Select: Jupyter Interface: JupyterLab Environment setup: TODO UPDATE ME Allocation: ebf11_d_g_gc_default Number of hours: 2 hours Node type: ACI-b GPU (either No GPU or 1 GPU) Memory per core: 4 GB Click Launch Wait while your job starts Once the Connect to JupyterLab Server button appears, click it The top row of tiles (labeled &amp;ldquo;Notebook&amp;rdquo;) should include a tile labeled &amp;ldquo;Julia 1.</description></item><item><title>ACI Remote Desktop</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/aci/remote_desktop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/aci/remote_desktop/</guid><description>Starting a Remote Desktop session on ACI To start a remote Desktop session:
Log into the ICDS-ACI Portal at https://portal.aci.ics.psu.edu/. Choose Interactive Apps, RHEL7 Interactive Desktop. Select &amp;ldquo;ebf11_d_g_gc_default&amp;rdquo; for allocation and &amp;ldquo;ACI-b GPU Core&amp;rdquo; for node type. (Alternatively, one might choose open for allocation and &amp;ldquo;ACI-i&amp;rdquo; for node type.) Click &amp;ldquo;Launch&amp;rdquo; Wait a little while, as your the system will submit a job to the scheduler. Once you have a button to start your session, click it.</description></item><item><title>SSH keys on ACI</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/aci/sshkeys/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/aci/sshkeys/</guid><description>For students using Roar for the first time, start a terminal on a Roar node, and run the following script
/gpfs/group/RISE/classroom/astro_528/scripts/updateKeys.sh once at the beginning of the semester.
This will:
Properly setting up keys for password-less ssh to compute nodes which is sometimes required by some distributed computing models, Generate keys for github, Modify ssh config file, and Set proper permissions on all ssh files/directories. I recommend that you do NOT enter a password for your ssh key.</description></item><item><title>Running Jupyter on a GPU node</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/aci/jupyter_gpu_nodes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/tips/aci/jupyter_gpu_nodes/</guid><description>TODO: Need to Update for Fall 2021 You can currently access a K4000 GPU on the ACI interactive nodes from the Jupyter notebook server. Students in the class can access more powerful P100 GPUs (with support for double precission arithmetic) via the CyberLAMP cluster by specifying the following PBS options:
-A cyberlamp_class -l qos=cl_class -l nodes=1:ppn=1:gpus=1 If you would like to run Jupyter on a GPU node, then you can try the following instructions kindly provided by Justin Petucci:</description></item></channel></rss>