<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Syllabus on PSU Astro 528</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/</link><description>Recent content in Syllabus on PSU Astro 528</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Basic Course Information</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/basic_info/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/basic_info/</guid><description>Course: Astro 528: High-Performance Scientific Computing for Astrophysics (Fall 2021) Class Meetings: 3:30-4:30pm Mondays &amp;amp; 1:30-3:00pm Thursdays in Davey Lab 538 (current plan) There is the possibiliy that some or all classes may transition on short notice to a remote synchonous or blended format due to health and safety concerns. Instructor: Eric Ford Email: ebf11 at psu dot edu Phone: x3-5558 Office Hours: Thursdays 3-4pm (or by appointment) via Zoom (see meeting ID inside Canvas) Website: https://psuastro528.</description></item><item><title>Course Topics</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/topics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/topics/</guid><description>Overview of Scientific Computing, High Performance Computing, Data Science &amp;amp; Big Data Priorities for Scientific Computing Types &amp;amp; Choices of Programming Languages Floating Point Arithmetic Best Practices for Scientific Programming Version Control (e.g., git) Testing Continuous Integration Documentation &amp;amp; Literate Programing Debugging Benchmarking &amp;amp; Profiling Reproducible Results &amp;amp; Workflows Packages, Environments, Containers &amp;amp; Images Efficient Workflows Optimizing Code Performance Modern Processors, Memory &amp;amp; Networking Architectures Choice of Algorithms Choice of Data Structures Serial Codes Shared Memory Systems (i.</description></item><item><title>Readings</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/readings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/readings/</guid><description>Textbooks The required textbooks for this course are:
Writing Scientific Software: A Guide to Good Style by Suely Oliveira, Cambridge University Press, 1st edition, September 18, 2006, ISBN-10: 0521858968. (I recommend considering a used version.) Think Julia: How to Think like a Computer Scientist by Ben Lauwens and Allen Downey, 1st edition, May 14, 2019. ISBN-10:1492045039 (I recommend using the version avaliable online for free.) I will also suggest readings from an optional textbook:</description></item><item><title>Assessed Work</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/assignments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/assignments/</guid><description>The assessed work for this course consists of computer lab/homework assignments (40%), a class project (50%) and class discussion (10%; including either contributing to class discussion and/or submitting reading questions. There are no exams. The class project will have several components and will be described in more detail below.
The planned assignment due dates are in the schedule section of the syllabus. Any revision to the due dates will be announced at the time they are assigned.</description></item><item><title>Requirements</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/requirements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/requirements/</guid><description>NEED TO UPDATE THIS PAGE Course Prerequisites This course is designed for Astronomy &amp;amp; Astrophysics graduate students. While Astro 501 is listed as a corerequsite by the registrar, that is primarily a formality, so that non-Astrophysics students will contact me to discuss their background before registering. Previously, we have had some graduate students from physics and engineering who did very well in the course. Of course, some extra thought may be required to figure out how concepts from the course presented in the context of astronomy or astrophysics could be applied to their own field of study.</description></item><item><title>Expectations</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/expectations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/expectations/</guid><description>Safety Students are required to follow all Penn State requirements related to safety, particularly in relation to the COVID-19 pandemic. All students, faculty, staff and visitors are required to wear masks at all times in all indoor public spaces, including the classroom. Students are expected to wear masks properly, covering the bridge of their nose and under their chin. While some students may be comfortable working closely with a partner, others may prefer to maintain physical distance.</description></item><item><title>Accomodations</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/accomodations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/accomodations/</guid><description>Academic Success, Learning Assistance, &amp;amp; Student Resources The Eberly College of Science is committed to the academic success of students enrolled in the College&amp;rsquo;s courses and undergraduate programs. When in need of help, students can utilize various College and University wide resources for learning assistance. (https://science.psu.edu/current-students/support-network)
Accomodations Note to Students with Disabilities:
Penn State welcomes students with disabilities into the University’s educational programs. Every Penn State campus has an office for students with disabilities.</description></item></channel></rss>