<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Syllabus on PSU Astro 528</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/</link><description>Recent content in Syllabus on PSU Astro 528</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Basic Course Information</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/basic_info/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/basic_info/</guid><description> Course: Astro 528: High-Performance Scientific Computing for Astrophysics (Fall 2021) Class Meetings: 3:30-4:30pm Mondays &amp;amp; 1:30-3:00pm Thursdays in Davey Lab 538 Instructor: Eric Ford Email: ebf11 at psu edot edu Phone: x3-5558 Office Hours: Thursdays 3-4pm or by appointment Website: https://psuastro528.github.io/</description></item><item><title>Course Topics</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/topics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/topics/</guid><description>Overview of Scientific Computing, High Performance Computing, Data Science &amp;amp; Big Data Priorities for Scientific Computing Types &amp;amp; Choices of Programming Languages Floating Point Arithmetic Best Practices for Scientific Programming Version Control (e.g., git) Testing Continuous Integration Documentation &amp;amp; Literate Programing Debugging Benchmarking &amp;amp; Profiling Reproducible Results &amp;amp; Workflows Packages, Environments, Containers &amp;amp; Images Efficient Workflows Optimizing Code Performance Modern Processors, Memory &amp;amp; Networking Architectures Choosing Algorithms Serial Codes Shared Memory Systems (i.</description></item><item><title>Readings</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/readings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/readings/</guid><description>Textbooks The required textbooks for this course are:
Writing Scientific Software: A Guide to Good Style by Suely Oliveira, Cambridge University Press, 1st edition, September 18, 2006, ISBN-10: 0521858968. (I recommend considering a used version.) Think Julia: How to Think like a Computer Scientist by Ben Lauwens and Allen Downey, 1st edition, May 14, 2019. ISBN-10:1492045039 (I recommend using the version avaliable online for free.) I will also suggest readings from an optional textbook:</description></item><item><title>Assessed Work</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/assignments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/assignments/</guid><description>The assessed work for this course consists of computer lab/homework assignments (50%) and a class project (50%). There are no exams. Contributions to class discussion (including submitting reading questions may be counted for up to 10% of the course grade (coming from lab/homework exercises). The class project will have several components and will be described in more detail below.
The planned assignment due dates are in the schedule section of the syllabus.</description></item><item><title>Requirements</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/requirements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/requirements/</guid><description>NEED TO UPDATE THIS PAGE Course Prerequisites This course is designed for Astronomy &amp;amp; Astrophysics graduate students. While Astro 501 is listed as a corerequsite by the registrar, that is primarily a formality, so that non-Astrophysics students will contact me to discuss their background before registering. Previously, we have had some graduate students from physics and engineering who did very well in the course. Of course, some extra thought may be required to figure out how concepts from the course presented in the context of astronomy or astrophysics could be applied to their own field of study.</description></item><item><title>Expectations</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/expectations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/expectations/</guid><description>Etiquette Students are expected to be civil and considerate in class. In particular, we want to create an environment where everyone feels comfortable asking questions and sharing imperfect code. Students should refrain from any actions that distract their classmates, instructor or the class. It&amp;rsquo;s understandable the cell phones will often be used for two factor authentication, but they should be silenced and put away during class once you&amp;rsquo;ve authenticated. Taking notes on laptops or looking up information relevant to class discussion is encouraged.</description></item><item><title>Accomodations</title><link>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/accomodations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://psuastro528.github.io/syllabus/accomodations/</guid><description>Penn State welcomes students with disabilities into the University&amp;rsquo;s educational programs. If you have a disability-related need for reasonable academic adjustments in this course, contact the Office for Disability Services (ODS) at 814-863-1807 (V/TTY). For further information regarding ODS, please visit the Office for Disability Services Web site at http://equity.psu.edu/ods/.
In order to receive consideration for course accommodations, you must contact ODS and provide documentation (see the documentation guidelines at https://equity.</description></item></channel></rss>